谁在那里  回答我  谁在那里
Who's there? Answer me. Who's there?
看来我的孩子受到了很好的照顾
I see my children are in good hands.
杰拉马瑞尔  是你吗
Jerlamarel... is that you?
是我
Yes.
你是来带他们走的吗
Did you come to take them away?
不  我是个逃亡者
No. I'm a fugitive.
我在别处还有事要干
And I have work to do elsewhere.
他们还是在你身边成长更安全
They are safer with you as they grow.
我跟着只是为了保证你们能找到庇护所
I stayed close to make sure that you would find the sanctuary.
并在山谷里杀熊
And to kill the bears in the valley.
我相信这应该是最后一只熊了
I believe this is the last bear.
这些孩子真是礼物
These children are a gift.
一定要好好照顾他们成长
Take great care of them as they grow.
可以把手给我吗
May I have your hand?
这  这是什么
What is... what is this?
在庇护所的瀑布边上  有一个小洞穴
At the sanctuary, beside the waterfall, there is a small cave.
爬进去  你会找到一个箱子
Climb in it. There you will find a box.
我给了你打开箱子的钥匙
I've given you the key to open that box.
去和帕丽丝谈谈
Speak to Paris.
告诉她  箱子里的东西是为我的孩子们准备
Tell her that the contents of the box are for my children.
在他们十二岁的时候打开箱子
Open the box when they are 12 summers old.
那时他们已能够理解里面的内容
Old enough to understand what is inside.
里面是什么
What is inside?
知识
Knowledge.
可以开启新世界的知识
Knowledge that will begin a new world.
甚至比我们祖先的世界还要好
Better even than the world of our ancestors.
总有一天  我们会团聚
Someday, we will be together.
给他们起名哈妮瓦和可风
Name them Haniwa and Kofun.
这样他们来找我时  我就能认出来
That way I'll know them when they come to me.
他们什么时候会去找你
And when will they come to you?
答案全在箱子中
The answers are all in the box.
等等  杰拉马瑞尔
Wait. Jerlamarel.
杰拉马瑞尔
Jerlamarel!
Jerlamarel.
杰拉马瑞尔
Jerlamarel!
我刚听见巴巴沃斯在喊那个巫师的名字
I just heard Baba Voss calling the witch's name.
这不让你心烦吗
Does this not bother you?
-这地方不讲法律吗  -这里无法可讲
- Is there no law in this place? - We are far away from the law here.
现在巴巴沃斯掌权  我们不敢冒犯他
Baba Voss is in charge now. We dare not offend him.
巴巴沃斯又不是法
Baba Voss is not the law.
神才是法
God is the law.
可能我们在这也无神可依吧
Perhaps we are far away from God here too.
就是巴巴沃斯
It was Baba Voss
还有帕丽丝下令把我的母亲
and it was Paris who condemned my mother...
你的亲姐妹  活活烧死
your own sister, to the bonfire.
为了什么
For what?
因为她质疑让他这样的男人
Because she questioned the wisdom of letting a man like him,
一个拒绝谈起过去的陌生人
a stranger, who would not speak of his past,
掌管这个村子吗
to be in charge of the village?
他们烧死她
They burned her
是因为怕她说出真相
because they feared she spoke the truth.
神不会忽略这些事
God doesn't lose sight of those things.
就算祂真的忽略了
And even if he did...
我绝对不会
I never will.
你去哪里了
Where have you been?
巴巴沃斯
Baba Voss?
发生什么了
What happened?
跟我说实话
Only the truth.
坐下  亲爱的
Sit down, my love.
为什么
Why?
因为杰拉马瑞尔来过了
Because Jerlamarel... happened.
它说我们会在折木的尽头找到她
It says we'll find her at the end of the fallen trunk.
我只听过传说
I've only ever heard stories.
我都不知道村子里
I didn't even know that we had a Shadow
有暗影生活在我们之中
living among us in the village.
所以才叫暗影  没人知道他们是谁
Oh, that's why Shadows are Shadows. No one knows who they are.
但是艾肯尼历来有一个暗影
But the Alkenny have always had a Shadow.
我在祭坛上给她留了一张字条
I left a note on the altar for her,
我再去的时候就不见了
and when I came back, it was gone.
她会来的
She will be here.
你要怎么知道它来了
And how will you know when it arrives?
我不知道  我从来没这样做过
I don't know. I've never done this before.
我猜她会让我们知道她来了
I presume she will make herself known to us.
你为什么一直说"她"
Why do you keep saying "she"?
因为暗影肯定是女人  男人太笨拙
Because Shadows are always women. Men are too clumsy.
那你觉得会是谁
So who do you think it is, then?
可能是每天都会和我们交谈的人
Somebody we probably talk to every day.
是个有能力隐藏身体的人
Somebody with the power to hide her body.
没人能同时在又不在
No one can both be and then not be all at once.
只有其他人动她才会动
She moves only when others move.
就连阿尤拉也听不见她
Even Ayuras can't hear her.
她心中无思  就连先知也感知不到她
She purges herself of thought. Even presages can't sense her.
她在另一个空间  无法察觉
She's in another place, undetectable.
就连狗都以为她们是石头
Even dogs think they're stone.
她来了
She is here.
暗影  你好
Shadow... I greet you.
暗影  我需要你跟踪一个人  村里的人
Shadow, I need you to shadow someone, someone in the village,
把你听到的一切都告诉我
and report everything you hear.
你不顺从的话  她不会回应
She will not respond unless you submit.
别动
Stand still!
暗影  你能满足我的请求吗
Shadow, will you do as I ask?
是同意的意思吗
Is that a yes?
两声是"是"  一声是"不"  对吗
Two for "yes," one for "no"? Yes?
暗影  那个人就是帕丽丝
Shadow, the person is Paris.
我们认为她是巫师  我们需要证据
We believe she is a witch. We need proof.
你能跟踪巫师吗
Can you shadow a witch?
暗影  你能跟踪巫师吗
Shadow, can you shadow a witch?
我们怎么报答你
And how shall we pay you?
暗影
Shadow?
他说"新世界"
"A new world," he said?
也许开启新世界后  旧的就会被毁掉
Perhaps in making a new world, the old will be destroyed.
只是个箱子而已  亲爱的
It's just a box, my love.
这是什么
What is it?
是给孩子的  也许是个玩具
It's for the children. Perhaps it is a toy.
不  这有寓意
No. It will have a meaning.
他做的所有事都有寓意
Everything he does has a meaning.
其中的深意我永远都参不透
Meaning of which I can never understand.
我擅长照顾人  不擅长理解人
I'm good for caring, not good for understanding.
巴巴沃斯  我肯定会选择能照顾我的男人
Baba Voss, I would always choose a man who can care of me
而不是能理解我的男人
over a man who understands me.
帕丽丝
Paris?
是我
Yes.
你丈夫请我来的
Your husband invited me.
杰拉马瑞尔亲口说我们必须和她商量
Jerlamarel himself said we must consult with her.
来  坐
Come, come.
箱子里还有什么
What else is in the box?
这条信息说  我们必须保持
This message says we must keep what is on top on top,
上下的顺序不能颠倒
and what is at the bottom on the bottom.
用树皮怎么打造一个新世界
How do we make a new world of tree bark?
微风也无法带来视觉
The breeze brings no visions either.
还有好多这种树皮
And many more of the same.
帕丽丝
Paris.
怎么了  你知道这些是什么
What? Do you know what they are?
是的
Yes.
这些是书
They... they are books.
书是什么
What are books?
我祖母给我讲过
My grandmother told me stories
她祖母的祖母给她讲过的故事
her grandmother's grandmother told her.
我梦见过她和书在一起
I dreamt them with her.
书是神圣的
Books are in the holy shape.
它们寂静无声  然而
They are silent, and yet
它们直接和想象对话
they speak directly into the imagination.
你可以烧掉它们  但它们比火更强大
You can burn them, but they are more powerful than fire.
亘古以来所有的知识都记录在内
All the knowledge of the ancient ones are put into them.
视觉时代的秘密
Secrets of the age of vision.
我祖母的祖母有她自己的书
My grandmother's grandmother had books of her own.
但是猎巫者把它们都烧了
But the Witchfinder burnt them all.
我以为  所有的书都被烧光了
I thought... all the books had been burnt.
杰拉马瑞尔说我们必须等12年
Jerlamarel said that we must wait 12 summers
才能把这些书给孩子们
before we give them to the children.
他一定是相信他们继承了
He must believe that they have inherited
他能倾听无声的能力
his ability to hear silence.
他可以相信  但不代表就是事实
He can believe, but that does not make it true.
我的孩子可能没有被诅咒
My babies may not be cursed.
诅咒
Cursed?
我们住在一个永远与世隔绝
We're here, living alone forever,
充满迷信的村子里
in a village filled with superstition.
也许你的孩子们不会永远待在这里
Maybe your children won't stay forever.
什么意思
Meaning what?
什么意思  帕丽丝
Meaning what, Paris?
在确定他们有这种能力之前
Until we know for certain that they have the ability,
我们之间不要有任何分歧
there must be no dispute between us.
我们一定要把它们当成珍贵的种子埋起来
We must bury them like precious seeds.
因为它们是来自杰拉马瑞尔的礼物
Because they are a gift from Jerlamarel.
而杰拉马瑞尔的礼物向来"很好"
And Jerlamarel's gifts are always good.
你还有其他主意吗  玛格拉
You know different, Maghra?
巴巴沃斯
Baba Voss...
把书埋到风信子树下
bury the books by the hyacinth tree.
接下来的12年  我们对此一个字都不要提
And for 12 summers, we will not speak a word of this.
暗影
Shadow?
Shadow.
我收到你的消息了
I got your message.
我来了
I'm here.
你在吗
Are you there?
暗影
Shadow?
她不肯说话
She wouldn't speak.
她把她听到的  用绳结记了下来
She tied what she heard.
有三个人在场  巴巴沃斯  帕丽丝和玛格拉
There were three present. Baba Voss, Paris, and Maghra.
他们说起了孩子
They spoke about the babies.
巫师呢
What of the witch?
只说起了孩子
The babies.
他们哭泣  吃奶  哼哼唧唧  没别的了
They're wailing, they're feeding, they're cooing, nothing else.
她就说了这些
This is what she said.
暗影撒谎
The Shadow is lying!
也许是的
You may be right.
她可以不回答我的问题
She may not answer my questions.
但是我要把巫师的消息透露出去
But I'm gonna send news of a witch.
然后猎巫者可以让他们...
And then the Witchfinders can ask them...
消息  你要怎么发消息
News? How are you going to send news?
漂流瓶
A message.
它会顺着溪流飘过数十个山谷
It will flow downstream through a dozen different valleys.
谁知道谁会捡到它呢
Who knows who will find it?
只有海狸会捡到
A beaver will find it.
但我可以一天扔两次
But I will do it twice a day.
甚至扔三次
Three times a day.
总有一天  我们的祈祷将得到回应
And one day, our prayers will be answered.
河流和山谷太多了  可能要好几年的时间
There are so many valleys and rivers. It will take years.
或许吧
Perhaps.
但我们还有希望
But we will have hope.
别动
Hold!
我的朋友
My friend.
我就知道会发现你一个人在这里
Knew I'd find you out here all by yourself.
你怎么样
How are things with you?
一切皆好
All is well.
那就好
Good.
你呢
And you?
你也一切都好吗
Is all well with you too?
你真的想知道吗
Do you really wanna know?
当然了
Of course.
现在  情况不太好
Things are, are not so good.
我睡不着
I have trouble sleeping.
听你这么说我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
我白天听说的一些事  让我晚上难以入睡
You see, I hear things during the day that keep me awake.
什么样的事
What sort of things?
我感觉到身边有强烈的不信任感
I feel a great mistrust around me.
我担心有人费尽心思地监视我
I fear someone may have even gone to great lengths to spy upon me
以及跟我亲近的人  就在我的家中
and those closest to me, inside my own home.
那几乎是不可能的
It is highly unlikely.
你和你姨妈对我和我的家人
It is no secret that you and your aunt
心怀怨恨  这可不是什么秘密
bear ill will towards me and my family.
我想着  如果有判断力欠缺的人
I thought if there was someone out there with poor judgment
试图挑衅我
to want to provoke me,
那你应该最清楚
you, of all people, might know them.
但你不知道  对吧
But you don't, do you?
没错  我不知道
No, I do not.
很好  这很好
Good. That's good.
我希望你记住  在这里我就是律法
I want you to remember, I am the law here.
任何人都可以来找我  坦承心中的想法
Anyone and everyone can come to me and speak their mind,
如果他们在诉说时勇敢地面对我
and if they face me when they speak,
那在他们面前的就是一个公正公平的人
they will meet a fair man, a just man.
也就是我现在的样子
The man that I am right now.
但如果让我听到风言风语
But if I hear whispers in the wind,
那我必会亲自找出说这些话的人
and I must discover the speaker myself,
然后他或她  将面对曾经的那个我
then he or she may face the man that I once was.
一个嗜好鲜血和恐怖的人
A man with the taste for blood and terror.
如果有人有话要说  盖瑟拜克斯
If someone has something to say, please, Gether Bax,
叫他们来找我说清楚
tell them to find me and say it...
别被我先揪出来
before I find them first.
都听好
Hear me!
你们没能向我提供我要求的信息
You have failed to give me the information I asked for.
因此你们失去了家园
And you've lost your homes.
立刻交代  这样你们不至于连性命也丢掉
Speak now so you may not lose your lives as well.
告诉我你们所知的
Tell me what you know
关于那个叫杰拉马瑞尔的异端者和恶魔的一切
about the heretic and devil called Jerlamarel.
告诉我你们所知的关于他孩子的一切
Tell me what you know about his children.
我们  我们什么都没听说
We... we hear nothing.
求求你了  放过我们吧
Please, I beg you, let us be.
如果你什么都没听说
If you've heard nothing,
那你的耳朵对我来说也毫无用处
then your ears are no use to me.
信使
Messenger!
有信息要传给女王
A report for the queen.
"我们搜索阳冢周围的山林
"We have been searching in the mountains
已经几个月了
of the Sun Grave land for months now.
我们向神祈求指引
We pray to God always for guidance,
但却没有信息  没有气味  没有记号  没有希望
but we get no word, no scent, no markers, no hope.
但阳冢地区的村庄都很分散
But the villages of the Sun Grave world are scattered.
有太多的山脉和人迹罕至的高原
There are many mountains and lost plateaux.
惧怕熊和狮子的人  都驻扎在自己的防卫措施内
The people fear bears and lions and remain inside their defenses.
所以
And, so,
我怀着沉重的心情  寻求您的指示
it is with heavy heart that I now seek your instruction.
我的任务结束了吗
Is my mission ended?
我认为现在已经无望了
I believe it is now hopeless.
我谦卑地请求让我们回到帕岩王国
I humbly request that we be allowed to return to Payan.
我依然是您忠心的仆人  塔玛奇俊"
I remain your devoted servant, Tamacti Jun."
能让我亲自读取消息吗
May I read the message for myself?
-我已经全部念给您听了  -给我
- I have read it to you in its entirety. - Give it to me.
我的手指很敏感  你可能遗漏了一些信息
I have very sensitive fingers. You may have missed something.
第一段确实是塔玛奇俊传来的
The first arm's length is indeed from Tamacti Jun.
第二段却不是
The second arm's length is not.
塔玛奇俊永远不会谦卑  他也不是仆人
Tamacti Jun is never humble, he's not a servant,
根据我和塔玛奇的秘密约定
and by secret agreement between Tamacti and I,
他每隔十个字就会打一个心形结  以避免有人伪造
he always ties a heart every tenth to avoid forgery,
萨克大人  这确定无疑是伪造的
and this, my Holy Lord Sak, is a forgery.
是别人写的  故意派你来配合  跪下
Others wrote it. You were sent. Kneel.
-陛下...  -我叫你跪下
- Your Majesty... - I said kneel!
塔玛奇俊是皇家税收人和猎巫者
Tamacti Jun is the royal tax collector and the royal Witchfinder.
他已经效忠我20年了
He's commissioned to serve 20 summers,
并且还将再效忠20年
and 20 summers he will serve.
在他效忠的每一天
And every single day of his service,
他都会猎杀杰拉马瑞尔
he will hunt for Jerlamarel.
因为憎恶和仇恨
For hatred and vengeance
是两匹给他拉车的野马
are the two wild horses pulling his carriage.
是谁派你来欺骗我的
Who sent you to lie to me?
其他担心的人
Others with concerns.
哪些其他人
Which others?
其他希望让您恢复理智的人  陛下
Others who wish to make you see reason, Your Majesty.
陛下  异端者杰拉马瑞尔已经消失了
Your Majesty, the heretic Jerlamarel is lost.
我们这里面临着麻烦
We have troubles here.
神圣之力正在消退
The holy power is fading.
永恒之墙的墙缝开始渗水
Water is coming through cracks in the eternal wall,
水面在升高
and the level is rising.
神灵现在的歌声只有两种声音
The gods now only sing with two voices.
人民正在质疑您的力量
People are questioning your power.
您需要将军队召回来守在这里  陛下
You need your army here, Your Majesty.
那些假结是谁打的
Who tied the false knots?
卡恩大人
Lord Carne.
纪夫人
Lady Zee.
还有吗
And more?
没有了
None.
说谎之人受死吧
Choke on your own lies.
我想祈祷
I wish to pray.
杰拉马瑞尔  我唯一的真爱
Jerlamarel... my one true love.
曾经  我也如这般和你一起祈祷
Once, I prayed with you like this.
曾经  我们不需要言语就能交流
Once, we spoke to each other without words...
但你现在已经不再跟我说话
but you no longer speak to me.
那么我就在祈祷时跟你说话
So I'll speak to you in a prayer.
杰拉马瑞尔  安然地回来吧
Jerlamarel... come home in peace...
让我孕育你的孩子
and beat your pursuers to my body.
我将宽恕你的罪过
I will forgive your sins.
快回来  让我诞下继承了你力量的孩子
Come back and give me children with the power, your power.
我将宣布视觉为异端邪教
I will proclaim the Vision heresy.
我将与神明断绝关系
I will renounce the gods.
因为我们的孩子将成为新神
For our children will be the gods.
我将成为你曾经否认的神
And I will be the god you once denied.
永远  永远
Forever and ever.
都听好
Behold...
卡恩大人和纪夫人
Lord Carne and Lady Zee...
我曾以为他们忠心于我
whom I thought to be faithful to me.
求你了  陛下
Please, Your Majesty!
我发现他们犯了叛国罪和伪造罪
I found them guilty of treason and forgery.
我们只是说出了事实真相
We only spoke the truth.
你们都知道的事实真相
The truth you all know.
她整日在这里想着杰拉马瑞尔
She only thinks of Jerlamarel when here, at home,
发动机一个个坏掉  水面在上升
the engines are breaking, the water is rising.
她不是神...
She is not a go...
这是实话
It is true.
我为拯救你们的生命
The battle I fight to save your lives...
拯救神圣的帕岩城  经历了一场苦战
and to save your holy Payan city is a hard one.
但我依然奋力抗争了
But I fight it
因为那是我们家族的命运
because that is the lot of my lineage.
如同神灵指引我的那样
As God instructs me,
祂许我多少神力  我就是怎样的神
I am a god as much as he allows.
作为神在地上的执行者  我阻止了毁灭
So, as his hands on earth, I hold back destruction,
让你们享受到冬暖夏凉  为防护栅栏注入魔力
warm the winter, cool the summer, put magic in our fences
阻拦狮子和熊的侵袭
against lions and bears
否则它们会伤害你们的孩子
who would otherwise destroy your children...
哪怕它们已经吃饱
even on full bellies.
但我经历的更伟大的战斗是对抗光明
But the greater battle I fight is against light...
那是一种将人类置于神明之上的力量
a power that puts man above God...
那种力量将再次
a power that would, once again,
为复原的世界套上枷锁
put leather reins and chains on a world restored.
我们的军队在外面  对抗着那些光明魔鬼
Our armies are out in the field, fighting these devils of light.
我们应该尊崇他们
We should honor them.
而不是背着他们密谋叛国
Not whisper treason behind their backs.
反对我
To speak against me...
就是加速光明和毁灭的再次到来
is to speed a return of light and destruction.
这绝不能被宽恕
It cannot be forgiven.
很遗憾
With regret,
老朋友们  只能去了
old friends... go.
♪我们是帕岩人♪
♪ We are Payan ♪
♪我们是神圣的♪
♪ We are holy ♪
♪我们是天选之子♪
♪ We are chosen ♪
♪我们是  我们是  我们是♪
♪ We are, we are, we are ♪
♪我们是帕岩人♪
♪ We are Payan ♪
♪我们是神圣的♪
♪ We are holy ♪
♪我们是天选之子♪
♪ We are chosen ♪
♪我们是♪
♪ We are ♪
三年后
我给孩子们带了一些蔷薇果来
I brought some rose fruit for the babies.
玛格拉
Maghra...
-我感到空气中...  -是的
- the air I feel... - Yes.
是的  没错
Yes, you do.
你感觉到悲伤  或许也有些快乐
You feel sorrow and joy somewhere, perhaps,
但主要是悲伤
but mostly sorrow.
给
Here.
这是他们最爱的玩具
Their favorite toy.
你想将它放在哪里都行  别弄出声
Place it anywhere, anywhere you like, just quietly.
哈妮瓦  可风  你们的玩具在哪儿
Haniwa, Kofun, where's your toy?
去找你们的玩具
Go find your toy.
你找到了吗
Do you have it?
乖女儿
Good girl.
给帕丽丝婶婶
Now give it to Aunty Paris.
去玩吧
Go play.
如果我盖住他们的眼睛  他们就找不到了
And if I cover their eyes, they can't do it anymore.
我已经知道很久了  但我...
I've known for a long time. And I ju...
我只是假装不知而已
I just pretended that I didn't know.
现在确定无疑了
And now it is certain.
对谁而言
To who?
巴巴
Baba!
过来  宝贝们  过来
Come here, my loves. Come.
你们先出去玩吧
You may go outside and play.
我等下就出来
I'll be right out.
我其实早就知道了  之前哈妮瓦抓着我的手
I have known since Haniwa grabbed at my hand
跟我说  太阳有个妹妹  只有晚上才出来玩
and told me the sun had a sister that came out at night to play.
我知道
I know.
看来杰拉马瑞尔跟你说的是真的  巴巴沃斯
So, what Jerlamarel told you was true, Baba Voss.
这对双胞胎是一个新世界的开始
These twins are the beginning of a new world.
我建议我们公开事实真相吧
I say we declare the truth.
他们是我的宝贝
They are my babies.
苏特拜克斯和盖瑟拜克斯已经说我们是巫师了
Already Souter Bax and Gether Bax speak of us as witches.
他们有朋友  而且越来越多
They have friends, more and more.
我建议我们隐瞒事实真相
I say we hide, we hide the truth.
杰拉马瑞尔说要等12年
Jerlamarel said 12 summers.
在那之前我们什么也不说
We say nothing until then.
在那之前  他们要闭上双眼活着
And until then, they will live with their eyes closed.
很久很久以前
Once upon a time,
有四个兄弟姐妹
there were four brothers and sisters
幸福快乐地生活在一个村子里
living happily together in a village,
就像我们的一样
just like ours.
他们每天一起劳作
They all worked together every day.
一个能调出最芳香的香水
One made the most fragrant perfume.
一个能烤出最香甜的蛋糕
Another baked the sweetest cakes.
一个能弹奏出最优美的乐曲
Another played the most exquisite music.
第四个能用丝绸织出如融雪般轻盈的
And the fourth wove silk for sheets and dresses
被单和衣裙
that felt like warm snow.
他们每天都快乐地分工合作
And they all worked happily together every day,
从来不争吵
and they never quarreled.
但有一天
But then one day,
有一个男孩来到村里
a boy came along
自称是他们失散多年的亲哥哥
who said he was their long-lost older brother.
但当四兄弟姐妹询问他负责做什么时
But when the sisters and brothers asked him what he did...
他说他告诉人们真相
he said he told people the truth.
"什么真相"  他们问道
"What truth?" they asked him.
"这个嘛"  他答道
"Well," he replied...
"我可以告诉你们  你们其中一人很英俊"
"I could tell you that one of you is very handsome..."
一人很美丽  一人很平庸
one is quite pretty, one is plain...
还有一人很丑陋"
"and one of you is very ugly."
他的话让四兄弟姐妹感到十分困惑
The family were very puzzled by his words...
因为  如果你还没猜到
because, if you hadn't guessed already,
其实他们四人的名字分别是
the names of these brothers and sisters
嗅觉  味觉  听觉和触觉
were Scent, Taste, Sound and Touch.
他们原本的世界里并无美丑之分
And there was no "ugly" and there was no "pretty" in their world.
"但分别是指谁呢"  他们问大哥
"But which one of us is which?" they asked him, their brother.
"既然你们无从得知  就不该在意"  他答道
"Well, since you can't know, you shouldn't care," he replied.
说完他就离开了
And, with that, he went to walk off.
"等等  你叫什么"  他们高声问他
"Wait! What's your name?" they called to him.
"我叫视觉"  他答道
"My name is Vision," he replied.
说完他便骑马离开  留下四人独自沉思
And with that, he rode away and left them all alone to wonder.
很快  四兄弟姐妹开始争辩
Soon, the family started quarreling
他们之中哪个美丽
about which one of them was beautiful
哪个丑陋
and which one was ugly.
他们四人都耗费太多时间
Each one of them spent so much time
思索视觉说过的话
wondering about what Vision had said...
导致香水不再芳香
that the perfume lost its scent...
蛋糕不再香甜
the cakes lost their taste,
音乐不再悦耳
the music lost all harmony,
丝绸也变得破旧开裂
and the silk became threadbare and torn.
直到有一天  他们再次聚在一起
Until, at last, one day they came together again...
决定忘记视觉对他们说过的话
and they decided to forget what Vision had told them.
因为在他到来之前  他们都满足于现状
Because before he came, they'd all been perfectly content.
不久后  他们又恢复了心满意足的生活
And soon, they were content again.
因为他们决定  有他们四个就足够了
Because they decided that just four was just enough.
从此  他们过着幸福快乐的生活
And they all lived happily ever after.
你好
Hi-ho.
Whoo-hoo. Hi.
我带了份礼物给双胞胎
I have brought a gift for the twins to share...
明天是他们的生日
for their birthday tomorrow.
河流解冻后  你就没再提起过
Since the river thawed, you haven't spoken of it.
提起什么
Of what?
我们一直等待这一天到来
We've been waiting for this day to come.
十二年了  玛格拉
Twelve years, Maghra.
当然了  你想做什么由你决定
Of course, you are free to do as you choose.
你真好啊  帕丽丝
Well, that is good of you, Paris.
如果你认为他们还是太年幼  你想等多久
If you think they are still too young, how long will you wait?
巴巴沃斯和我已经决定了
Baba Voss and I have made a decision.
已经埋葬的秘密就永远不要挖出来
What is buried stays buried... forever.
那就是你的选择吗
That is your choice?
是我们共同的选择
It's our choice.
没什么能离间我们  帕丽丝  包括你
Nothing comes between us, Paris, not even you.
就这样让他们闭上双眼在这里成长  生活
So they just walk around with their eyes closed and grow,
直到死去吗
live, die here.
-只在这里...  -这是为了保命
- And only here... - To live!
难道这不是最重要的吗  帕丽丝
That is the thing. No, Paris?
我对他们只有这个冀望  就是活下去
That is what I want for them, that they live.
如果他们的秘密泄露了
If their secret should slip,
如果箱子里的东西暴露了他们的能力
if something from that box should give them away,
如果出现什么意外
if something, anything were to happen,
而且有无数可能发生的意外
and a thousand other "ifs,"
他们就会被烧死
they would burn.
或是如果箱子里的书籍叫他们离开村子
Or if the books in the box should tell them to leave the village
结果他们沦落狮腹和熊腹
and they become food for lions and bears,
那他们也会死
then they will die.
人死了  双眼就会永远闭上了
And if you're dead, your eyes are closed forever.
总有一天  会有人发现我们  发现他们
One day, someone will find us, will find them.
玛格拉  他们必须做好准备
Maghra, they need to be prepared.
-够了  -不  不够
- Enough! - No, not enough!
这种生活远远不够
This life is not enough.
你的理由也不够
Your excuse is not enough.
我不需要给你任何理由
I don't need to give you any excuses.
那杰拉马瑞尔呢
What about Jerlamarel?
杰拉马瑞尔  他可没有养育这两个孩子
Jerlamarel? Jerlamarel did not raise these children.
他没有帮过他们退烧
He did not break their fevers.
也没有哄过他们睡觉
He did not love them to sleep
因为他走了  浪迹天涯
because he was gone, just wandering.
你的声音
Your voice.
你恨他
You hate him.
为什么
Why?
玛格拉
Maghra?
而且你为何把恨意发泄到孩子身上
And why are you taking your hate out on them?
妈妈
Mama!
你走吧  帕丽丝
Go away, Paris.
我想和我的孩子们单独相处
I want to be with my children.
帕丽丝
Paris.
进来  坐吧
Hey, come in. Come sit.
我的宝贝们
Oh, my babies.
你们长大了  生日快乐
Oh, my big ones, happy birthday.
你们今天十二岁了
You are 12 years old today.
天啊
My.
十二年了  你们都保守着一个秘密
For 12 years, you have kept a secret.
并且你们把这秘密保守得很严实
And you have kept it very well.
我想知道  你们能再守住一个秘密吗
I wonder, could you keep another?
是什么
What is it?
是一种只有你们能享用的东西
It is for you and for you only.
这是有史以来最伟大的生日礼物
It is the greatest birthday gift of all time.
是什么东西
What are they?
是书
They are books.
我们认为是书
We think they are books.
给  这些是指示
Here. Here are the instructions
指导你们听见书中所言之物
that will help you hear what the books are saying.
是谁给的指导
Instructions from who?
你们的父亲
From your father.
爸爸能了解些什么
What does Dad know about this?
不是
No.
是你们真正的父亲
From your true father.
什么
What?
我只知道你们的母亲告诉我的只言片语
I only know what your mother told me.
我本来希望她能亲自告诉你
I was hoping that she would tell you herself.
我们已经有父亲了
We already have a father.
我知道  并且他非常爱你  可风
I know, who loves you so very much, Kofun.
哈妮瓦  但还有个男人
Haniwa... there is also a man...
从暴风雪中救了你们的母亲
who rescued your mother in a blizzard.
她是这么说的
That's the story she told.
她当时迷路了  你们的父亲救了她
She was lost, and he saved her.
然后他和她在一起了
And he stayed with her.
当她来到我们的村庄时
And when she came to our village,
已经怀上了你们这对双胞胎
you two, twins, were already inside her.
-他的名字叫杰拉马瑞尔  -不  不
- His name is Jerlamarel. - No, no.
-等等  哈妮瓦  -可风
- Wait, Haniwa. - Kofun.
-哈妮瓦  -他绝不可以告诉任何人
- Haniwa. - He mustn't tell anyone.
给  把这信息拿去你自己看
Here. Take the message and read it.
你很勇敢  去吧
You are brave. Go.
或许我们就是巫师
Maybe we're witches.
或许关于视觉的那些故事是真的
Maybe the stories about vision are true.
不
No.
事实真相在我手里
I have the truth in my hands.
很快我就会知道  但你却不会
Soon I will know and you will not.
念出来吧
Go ahead.
"很久很久以前
"Once upon a time,"
几乎所有人类都拥有你们所拥有的力量
almost all humans had the power that you have.
人类利用这种力量  以及头脑智慧的力量
Human beings used this power, and the power of their minds,
征服世界
to conquer the world.
他们造出了可以飞行的机器
They built machines that could fly,
可以让人隔着千万里对话的机器
machines that could speak across thousands of miles.
他们甚至坐着巨大的飞船离开了地球
They even left the earth in giant ships.
跟他们强大的力量一样
Such was their power,
他们的存在开始超越地球的承载力
they began to outgrow the earth
然后毁掉了地球
and destroy it.
有人说是神剥夺了他们的视觉
Some say sight was taken from them by God
以阻止这颗星球被他们毁灭
to save the planet from destruction.
但经过这么多年  视觉又开始恢复了
But after so many years, the gift of light is being restored,
只赐给天选之人
given only to chosen people
并指导他们重建世界
with an instruction to build the world again.
我是你们的父亲
I am your father.
我将这天赐的能力传给了你们
And I have passed this gift on to you.
你们的职责就是发挥它的用途
It is your duty to make use of it.
从我留给你们的书中学习知识
Learn from the books I have left.
我精心挑选了这些书
I have chosen the books with care.
我还留下了一些指示  等你们觉得
I have also left instructions where you should go
你们强大到可以离开村庄时  就去那个地方吧
when you feel you are strong enough to leave your village.
我会等着你们的到来
When you come, I will be waiting.
我们将一起  重建新世界
Together, we will begin the world anew.
爱你们的慈父...
With all my love, your loving father...
杰拉马瑞尔"
"Jerlamarel."
我们该怎么做
What should we do?
你打开了箱子
You opened the box.
是的  巴巴沃斯
I did, Baba Voss.
没有经过我们的允许
Without permission.
杰拉马瑞尔从熊爪下救了他们和你的命
Jerlamarel saved their lives from a bear, and yours.
他建造了一座桥
He built a bridge.
指引我们的部落来到安全的地方
And guided our tribe to safety.
他对你只有一个请求
And he made one request of you:
「让他们学习知识」
"Let them learn."
让他们发现事实真相
Let them discover the truth.
然后让他们自己做选择
Then let them choose.
玛格拉会把书都烧掉的
Maghra will burn the books.
-那就别告诉她  -你想让我欺骗她吗
- So do not tell her. - You would have me lie?
多年来  出于善意
For years, you told the twins
你一直告诉双胞胎  你就是他们的父亲
you were their father, out of kindness.
现在你也要用这份善意去对玛格拉
Now, you must be kind to Maghra.
沉默不是欺骗
Silence is not a lie.
我听到他们在谈论要离开这里
I heard them talking about leaving.
你知道他们总有一天必须要离开
You know they must someday.
-等他们离开时...  -不行
- And when they leave... - No.
等他们离开时  书将传授他们知识
When they leave, the books will give them knowledge.
巴巴沃斯  你是个好人
Baba Voss, you are a good man.
-但你并非一直是好人  -够了
- But you have not always been. - That is enough.
虽然我们躲藏在这里
Just because we are hiding here
但这并不代表世界已经变了
doesn't mean the world has changed.
但是巴巴  双胞胎可能就是改变世界的力量
But the twins, Baba, the twins might be the change.
他们是希望  巴巴
They are hope, Baba.
想想看你见证过的事
Think of the things you have witnessed.
想想看你做过的事
Think of the deeds you have done.
回报这个世界吧  巴巴
Pay the world back, Baba.
沉默不是欺骗
Silence is not a lie.
巴巴
Baba?
别浪费木头了  我来帮你暖身子
Don't waste a log. I'll keep you warm.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事  一切都好
Yes. Everything is all right.
上床来吧
Come to bed.
你拿了什么书
What do you got?
《杀死一只知更鸟》
哈珀·李
你呢
You?
《1984》
乔治·奥威尔